<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Textures</title>
    <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Textures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://riley-wilson.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Juan Carlos Ferrero academy - a review</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2025-10-01-jcf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2025-10-01-jcf/</guid>
      <description>I attended the “adultos” program at the Juan Carlos Ferrero (JCF) academy for a week in September 2025. I loved it.
My review has two parts. In the first, I share reasons why I enjoyed the program, and why the same may lead others to not. The second covers logistics and miscellanea.
What I loved and you may hate
Spanish Tennis
Why are the Spanish so good at tennis? Facile answers include “tennis is popular so all their best athletes play” and “they grow up on clay, clay is harder, and so they’re better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epistemic anguish at the tennis courts</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2025-05-25-epistemic-dread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2025-05-25-epistemic-dread/</guid>
      <description>I
There are many ways to play tennis poorly. There are failures of athleticism, where the feet are too slow or you have the cardio of a Koala. There are failures of judgment, where the wrong shot is chosen at the wrong time. The most existentially painful are failures of technique. These occur when you have the wrong grip, step with the wrong foot, swing from the outside-in rather than inside-out, or commit one of the dozens of errors that prevent perfect and reliable energy transfer from your body to the ball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing Shulman on intelligence explosions</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2023-06-25-shulman-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2023-06-25-shulman-ai/</guid>
      <description>Carl Shulman is a Research Associate at the Future of Humanity Institute. He recently appeared on Dwarkesh Patel&amp;rsquo;s podcast to discuss what he calls an &amp;ldquo;intelligence explosion.&amp;rdquo; I am an AI newbie. To better understand Shulman, I decided to reconstruct the former&amp;rsquo;s arguments as he presented them for Dwarkesh. I am ignoring the latter part of their discussion about alignment. Please note my prior knowledge of AI is limited. I am relying on Cunningham&amp;rsquo;s law to help me learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards measuring WTA court speeds</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2023-05-17-wta-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2023-05-17-wta-conditions/</guid>
      <description>Professional tennis players have unstable working conditions. It&amp;rsquo;s normal to finish a tournament Sunday in North America and then fly to Europe by Tuesday for another. Even within a continent players often to flit between cities, only staying in one location as long as they&amp;rsquo;re winning. In 2019, the month of September for many WTA professionals had stops in Zhengzhou, Osaka, Wuhan, and Beijing. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard players describe their time on tour as a blur of hotel rooms occassionally interrupted by tennis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior to, and after, lifestyle</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2023-02-23-lifestyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2023-02-23-lifestyle/</guid>
      <description>I used to be a brand philistine. For me, a brand was a basic signal of quality and nothing else. There were cost-conscious brands like Kroger Basics for groceries and Sketchers for shoes. If you wanted to get fancy, you could upgrade to Erewhon or Lacoste, buy a Mercedes rather than a Honda, or shop at Saks on Fifth rather than Nordstrom. Does Erewhon mayo taste better than Kroger mayo? Probably a little.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Party Seeking</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2022-12-15-party-seeking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2022-12-15-party-seeking/</guid>
      <description>Seth and Evan have returned home from their first year of college. Despite high school hijinks, they&amp;rsquo;ve found the tertiary social scene difficult: weekly ragers never materialized. In the last year, they&amp;rsquo;ve only attended three parties between them.
Seth: I don&amp;rsquo;t understand it. There are parties everywhere in college but I can&amp;rsquo;t get invited to any of them.
Evan: I feel you. Nobody seems to want me at their party, either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skip the small talk</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2022-10-08-skip-the-small-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2022-10-08-skip-the-small-talk/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a party. At the beginning, the host tells the attendees there are only two rules:
You can&amp;rsquo;t talk about work You can&amp;rsquo;t talk about cities Standard conversational crutches will not work tonight. Yet, projected in a prominent place, is a list of questions. Conveniently, these are the sorts of questions you&amp;rsquo;d ask someone at a specific kind of gathering. They&amp;rsquo;re a little quirky, slightly strange. Each wants to land at the intersection of probing and whimsical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulations on persistence</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2022-07-07-simulations-on-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2022-07-07-simulations-on-persistence/</guid>
      <description>Pick a skill you want to improve. It can be anything. Perhaps you’re keen on the oboe or want to graduate from paint-by-numbers to something more avant-garde. Or, you want to get in shape, learn new mathematics, or start a new career. Regardless, in a year’s time, you want to be substantially better at some thing than you are now.
You read internet blogs, so you’re compelled to model out your future progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paris Notes</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2022-01-31-paris_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2022-01-31-paris_notes/</guid>
      <description>This trip was something of a trial by fire. Two years ago, I was itching for international travel and felt ready for it. I wanted it just as bad now, but was less ready. Living through a pandemic worked a change in my psychology. I now crave stability and predictability more than I am willing to admit, and interacting with others has been more difficult than ever. Traveling is not kind to either of these traits, and I learned that the hard way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startups as status</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2021-11-21-startups-as-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2021-11-21-startups-as-status/</guid>
      <description>Status
My internet education has taught me to see the world in terms of status.1 Keeping tabs on status inflows and outflows can give a plausible explanation to almost any social puzzle. Why do people say X in conversation? (A: To be the high-status individual). Why do people do [tacky thing]? (A: it’s high-status in their social sphere, not yours). What explains big chunks of modernity? (A: We’re — allegedly — drunk on status).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalizations from competitive tennis</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2021-09-13-tennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2021-09-13-tennis/</guid>
      <description>I played competitive tennis growing up and was fairly decent. I had a racquet in my hand at around 5, played tournaments since 10, and had my relative singles ability peak around 14. I still play often, and most recently was a hitting partner for the UCLA’s women’s tennis team.
The upshot is that I’ve been in/around the game for a while. When I was younger, tennis was my only model about risk/reward/accomplishment/the world, so it heavily influenced my thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Portland</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2021-08-10-a-thought-on-portland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2021-08-10-a-thought-on-portland/</guid>
      <description>Every city, according to Paul Graham, tries to tell you something. For instance, walking around New York you might get the sense you need to be more fashionable, or make more money. A stroll through downtown San Francisco might prod you to join a startup, or at least work in technology. The culture of a city tugs at you, hinting you should be more X and less Y. It’s the place softly whispering what it wants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Afeyan on America</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2021-01-14-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2021-01-14-america/</guid>
      <description>Noubar Afeyan is the CEO of Moderna. His thoughts about America, as expressed in an interview with Tyler Cowen, struck me. For context, Afeyan is an Armenian-Lebanese immigrant.
The idea of being an &amp;ldquo;American by choice&amp;rdquo; is really interesting.
COWEN: Last question. How do we attract more people like you to come to America?
AFEYAN: Be America.
COWEN: What does that mean?
AFEYAN: What I mean is recognize that the country is, itself, one giant experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feel bad about us, feel good about the world</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-10-18-us-bad-world-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-10-18-us-bad-world-good/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally I meet someone with a really awful view of human nature. They look at the world, see all the ways we fail to cooperate, and conclude humanity has been doomed from the start. To them, there’s something like an inherent deficit of altruism or foresight that prevents us from solving our most pressing problems. Specifically, they tend to be disappointed with progress on climate change or nuclear weapons and are pretty dour as a result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tennis and probability</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-08-23-tennis-prob/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-08-23-tennis-prob/</guid>
      <description>The code used for the simulations can be found here.
I.
Imagine there’s a tennis match in Kyrgyzstan between two players you’ve never heard of. You don’t know their rankings, match histories, or even what they look like, but you’re tasked with predicting who will win. The only piece of information at your disposal is player1 has a p chance of winning any given point against player2. In other words, if player1 and player2 played 100 points, on average player1 would win p*100 of these points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability and God</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-05-22-prob-and-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-05-22-prob-and-god/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally, rare things happen to us.
You might land a competitive job (3/100), appear on the big screen at a sporting event (1/70,00), or win the lottery (1/12,271,512). It&amp;rsquo;s also possible for you to get a US green card (1/126), be struck by lightning (1/700,000), or have an idea so good it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;like getting struck by lightning&amp;rdquo; (1/???).
Whether it&amp;rsquo;s good or bad when the improbable becomes actual, there&amp;rsquo;s always a question lurking in the background: is this evidence of anything?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemics and ethnic violence</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-04-21-pandemics-ethnic-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-04-21-pandemics-ethnic-violence/</guid>
      <description>We begin with two questions:
Under what conditions will a population persecute an ethnic minority during and after a pandemic? Who is most likely to instigate the violence? Their answers are important. In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, a deadly coronavirus has surfaced in Wuhan, China, and has now spread around the world. Some hold Asians responsible for the pandemic and act on their prejudice. A 16-year-old Asian-American boy in the San Fernando Valley was assaulted and sent to the emergency room after being accused of having the virus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I didn&#39;t check my grades for two years</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-01-12-no-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-01-12-no-grades/</guid>
      <description>By the time college rolled around, I had made the decision not to check my grades at all. They had, quite literally, ruled my life during high school, and I was intent on making sure the future was different. This was not (fully) an irresponsible retreat from reality, but the consequence of some positions I began to hold about schools and learning. As a result, up until the end of my sophomore year, I never knew what letter grade I had received in a class or even what my GPA was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did household appliances actually save time?</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-01-03.appliances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2020-01-03.appliances/</guid>
      <description>I used to have this idea that the introduction of electric appliances circa 1960 dramatically reduced the number of hours people, especially housewives, spent on domestic tasks. The thought is pretty intuitive. It&amp;rsquo;s quicker to wash clothes with a washing machine than with a tub and washboard. Dishwashers are more efficient than washing dishes by hand. In the span of a couple of years, I thought, American housewives had much more free time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts at 2019</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-12-28-thoughts-at-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-12-28-thoughts-at-21/</guid>
      <description>originally titled &amp;lsquo;What I&amp;rsquo;ve learned at 21&amp;rsquo;
Hopefully, this blog post is the first step of what will become a lifelong project. I already journal every day and record some of what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned there, but making a public list helps me clarify my thoughts and allows friends to challenge them. In the future, it can also afford me an opportunity to publicly affirm or refute something I said in previous years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is becoming a lawyer a good investment? Part III</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-09-09-law-school-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-09-09-law-school-3/</guid>
      <description>In part 1, we described the hypothetical students used in this investigation and calculated the opportunity cost of going to law school for each of them. In part 2, we factored in tuition and university fees and arrived the amount of income a new JD would need to earn to do &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo; than their non-lawyer doppelgänger. Part 3 is where we draw conclusions. In order to do so, we&amp;rsquo;re going to revisit the concept of hurdle compensation that we developed in the last post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is becoming a lawyer a good investment? Part II</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-08-12-law-school-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-08-12-law-school-2/</guid>
      <description>In the last post, we described the hypothetical students we are using for this investigation and considered and the type of income they would be missing if they chose to go to law school. Now, we’ll add tuition to the total cost and see how much each would need to earn as lawyers to “break even,” so to speak.
Step 3: tuition and totals
Tuition varies greatly between institutions. In the most egregious of circumstances, you can expect to pay up to $77,000 a year at fancy private law school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is becoming a lawyer a good investment? Part I</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-07-07-law-school-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-07-07-law-school-1/</guid>
      <description>Like many in unmarketable majors, I&amp;rsquo;ve briefly toyed with the idea of becoming a lawyer. Not necessarily because I have a deep interest in the law, but because going to law school is the ultimate vindication for your humanities degree.
My personal interest passed quickly, but curiosity lingered about the profession. Why do people become lawyers? Is it really as miserable as I&amp;rsquo;ve heard? Is it even a sound financial decision?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efference copies everywhere</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-03-08-efference-copies-everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-03-08-efference-copies-everywhere/</guid>
      <description>I’m writing a paper right now about efference copies in nematode worms and what they can tell us about perception. The more I learn, the more impressed I am with the little guys, and all of the strange minor procedures organisms undergo so they can function.
I’ll start with the issue that faces the worms. First, they are super simple creatures. They only have 302 neurons (compare to 250,000 in a fruit fly) and thus have a limited repertoire of behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience machines and video games</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-02-04-experience-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/posts/2019-02-04-experience-machines/</guid>
      <description>Note this post was probably posted earlier than the date. What&amp;rsquo;s on record is when I ported this from a squarespace to a wordpress site.
Robert Nozick in his Anarchy, State and Utopia asks us to imagine a machine that we can plug into and it will simulate anything we desire. While we’re inside, we can experience the joys associated having a fulfilling job, listening to good music, falling in love, or talking with friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>What do you wanna know? Here are some fast facts:
Grew up in Portland, Oregon. Lived in Los Angeles, Berkeley, Las Vegas, Austin, New York, and Cambridge since. My only online presence is this blog and LinkedIn. The blog is better. I grew up playing tennis and still play tournaments when I can You&amp;rsquo;ll learn much more about me from the rest of the blog than this page. Feel free to email me about anything (seriously).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-books</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/read/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/read/</guid>
      <description>These are non-books I enjoy.
Andrea Petkovic Hugh Clarke Psmith&amp;rsquo;s bookshelf Baseline Intelligence The Secrets of Spanish Tennis (this was originally a book) Winning Ugly Testament of a furniture dealer How to skate a 10k King Richard 55 burgers 55 fries Art Deco </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/quotes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It is a safe rule to apply that, when a mathematical or philosophical author writes with a misty profundity, he is talking nonsense.&amp;rdquo;
-A.N. Whitehead
&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s like asking me &amp;lsquo;if a frog was a number, would it be divisible?&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;
-Tyler Burge
“To get an education, you’re probably going to have to fight against the institution that you find yourself in — no matter how prestigious it may be. (in fact, the more prestigious the school, the more you’ll probably have to push).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/stats/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The most important questions of life are, for the most part, really only problems of probability.&amp;rdquo; -Laplace Here are a bunch of resources I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered as well as notes I&amp;rsquo;m typing up. I&amp;rsquo;ve had prior exposure to multivariable calculus, linear algebra, and upper-div probability and statistics. I&amp;rsquo;m not starting from scratch, so I&amp;rsquo;m unsure how helpful these would be to someone who was. Your mileage may vary.
I&amp;rsquo;m very open to suggestions/comments!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words</title>
      <link>http://riley-wilson.github.io/words/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://riley-wilson.github.io/words/</guid>
      <description>Susurrus Whispers Ursine Of bears Haruspex Ancient Roman priest specialized in reading omens from entrails Abseil Rappel Sessile Fixed in place Recrudesce Recurrence Treacle Obsequiousness Arriviste A selfish parvenu Mésalliance A disadvantageous marriage Apotropaic The power to avert bad luck Manqué Having failed to achieve potential Autochthonous Indigenous Bosky Wooded Prodrome An early symptom of disease Detumescense The process of releasing tension Pusillaniumous Showing cowardice Orison A prayer Lucre Money, dishonestly acquired Paramour Lover of one married.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
